[{"answer": "Well, I think a lot of mistruths have been written about Phoebe, and I think that it was time to take her back, to reclaim her as ours and to put an end to some of the stories that have been going around.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 17, "question": "Why are you doing it?", "qSentId": 16}, {"answer": "Very much so.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 22, "question": "Were you taken aback by the kind of worldwide attention?", "qSentId": 21}, {"answer": "It was devastating to blame Phoebe.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 35, "question": "Is that what's really got to you?", "qSentId": 34}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 51, "question": "August 2009?", "qSentId": 50}, {"answer": "I was taking a career break.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 59, "question": "What was the motivation?", "qSentId": 58}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 68, "question": "Very different, I imagine, to the place you arrived to in America?", "qSentId": 67}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 76, "question": "How they would adapt?", "qSentId": 75}, {"answer": "Extraordinarily intelligent and vivacious and a great sense of humor, and a foodie.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 82, "question": "What kind of girl was she, Phoebe?", "qSentId": 81}, {"answer": "In ways, she was.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 87, "question": "Was she a confident girl?", "qSentId": 86}, {"answer": "Phoebe, she had -- she had a run-in with some girls before.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 99, "question": "What happened before that made you feel that?", "qSentId": 98}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 101, "question": "In Ireland?", "qSentId": 100}, {"answer": "That will be no problem.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 114, "question": "What did they say to you?", "qSentId": 113}, {"answer": "November.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 120, "question": "When did you discover for the first time that Phoebe was being bullied?", "qSentId": 119}, {"answer": "She wouldn't tell me.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 143, "question": "What could you deduce?", "qSentId": 142}, {"answer": "Never.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 148, "question": "Did she ever say what it was about?", "qSentId": 147}, {"answer": "Well, once in December she told me that one -- one of the girls involved in a new incident of bullying kept coming up to her in the hallways and screaming at her.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 150, "question": "Never?", "qSentId": 149}, {"answer": "But she wasn't -- the bullying on Facebook, the cyber bullying that has been put out by people was just a small component of the bullying of Phoebe.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 158, "question": "ORGAN: Did she know that these girls were using social media like Facebook and so on to bully her as well?", "qSentId": 157}, {"answer": "I don't think until the last day, really.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 192, "question": "Had she confided in anybody about how bad she was feeling?", "qSentId": 191}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 203, "question": "This is a systematic abuse of somebody, isn't it?", "qSentId": 202}, {"answer": "One of the bullies the next day was overheard saying, \"done.\"", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 207, "question": "You know?", "qSentId": 206}, {"answer": "Well, she got what she deserved, that was another one.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 213, "question": "To drive somebody to suicide and they just put \"done\" on Facebook?", "qSentId": 212}, {"answer": "I honestly don't know.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 218, "question": "Why were they so determined to force Phoebe into what eventually happened?", "qSentId": 217}, {"answer": "It's astounding that there was never a stop mechanism, you know, internal stop mechanism for some of these kids to say, this is going too far.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 221, "question": "It's wicked, isn't it?", "qSentId": 220}, {"answer": "It was -- it was very painful because, you know, you realize as a parent that no matter what I did, no matter how many times I called the school, no matter how many people I might have spoken to there, that she didn't stand a chance there.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 230, "question": "What is your reaction when you see, again, Gus Sayer saying that so soon after Phoebe died?", "qSentId": 229}, {"answer": "I didn't know that there were a fairly good number of teachers who witnessed things.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 232, "question": "ORGAN: What did you find out after her death about what else had been going on that you weren't aware of?", "qSentId": 231}, {"answer": "Maybe both.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 255, "question": "As a teacher or as a parent?", "qSentId": 254}, {"answer": "As a mother, I think that had the school intervened the way they should have intervened, if they had followed up the way they should have followed up, that Phoebe would still be here.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 267, "question": "And as a mother?", "qSentId": 266}, {"answer": "I'd like to actually clarify, because I know that there are some journalists that -- that think that prison terms were on the cards.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 290, "question": "Do you feel that justice was done?", "qSentId": 289}, {"answer": "I think even having the charges brought was - was justice for Phoebe and for so many other kids who are bullied that - what Betsy Scheibel and Beth did was they kind of threw down the gauntlet.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 296, "question": "Do you feel that you got justice for Phoebe?", "qSentId": 295}, {"answer": "It's massive.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 309, "question": "I mean the circle of people that get so damaged by this kind of thing is huge, isn't it?", "qSentId": 308}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 334, "question": "Has she ever said anything to you, Sharon Velasquez?", "qSentId": 333}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 336, "question": "Nothing?", "qSentId": 335}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 338, "question": "Never a word to you?", "qSentId": 337}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 340, "question": "Did any of them write you?", "qSentId": 339}, {"answer": "I did.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 356, "question": "ORGAN: Did you feel that remorse was sincere?", "qSentId": 355}, {"answer": "Oh, yes.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 375, "question": "That these things are allowed to happen unless you put a lid on them?", "qSentId": 374}, {"answer": "Well, simply put the evidence brought us to the point where charges were appropriate.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 398, "question": "Why this case and what have been the repercussions legally since you took the actions you took?", "qSentId": 397}, {"answer": "Well, we looked at the school behavior.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 406, "question": "From a strictly legal point of view, how culpable do you think the school was in terms of not tackling this bullying before it was too late?", "qSentId": 405}, {"answer": "Oh, absolutely.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 415, "question": "Did you pick up on that?", "qSentId": 414}, {"answer": "Well, they were tried as youthful offenders.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 426, "question": "How did that come about and what have been the implications of that for future cases now involving bullying?", "qSentId": 425}, {"answer": "I think in some ways, yes.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 437, "question": "But do you feel that what happened with this case is making a real impact now on bullying in schools in America?", "qSentId": 436}, {"answer": "Well, it doesn't - essentially what it does is it mandates the schools to report incidences of bullying should they believe that that - an act is one of bullying.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 445, "question": "In simple terms, what is that law?", "qSentId": 444}, {"answer": "Well, ideally, I would like it to be that - to treat children in a more civilized manner and know boundaries.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 450, "question": "Coming up , what would you like the legacy to be?", "qSentId": 449}, {"answer": "Well, ideally I would like it to be that humans just treat each other in a more civilized manner and no boundaries.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 470, "question": "What would you like the legacy to be?", "qSentId": 469}, {"answer": "No, I'm not.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 473, "question": "You're not?", "qSentId": 472}, {"answer": "Oh, absolutely.", "docId": "111204pmt", "aSentId": 478, "question": "And actually if the legacy is that in future, schools are just more aware, they take more action earlier and some lives can be saved rather than lost because of what's happened, that is at least a positive that comes out of this hell for you, isn't it?", "qSentId": 477}]